Finding Aid for Occupational Education Program (University of Michigan) Records, 1949-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Occupational Education Program (University of Michigan) records 1949-1980
University of Michigan. Occupational Education Program.
87266 Bimu C204 2
Records, 1949-1980, of the Occupational Education Program (formerly the department of vocational education) of the School of Education of the University of Michigan; contain history, minutes of staff meetings, reports, correspondence, program review files, committee records and subject files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
5 linear feet
The records were received from the Occupational Education Program (donor no. 1220.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Occupational Education Program is a successor to the Department of Vocational Education, subsequently called the Department of Vocational Education and Practical Arts, which was established following the Smith-Hughes Act of 1917. It provided for the training of teachers of technical and industrial arts subjects.
The records of the Occupational Education Program contain a history of the program, annual reports (1919-1978), minutes of staff meetings (1950-1980), reports to the Extension Service and State Office of Vocational Education, program review and curriculum development files, correspondence and subject files.
Subjects:
Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Vocational Education Dept.; University of Michigan. School of Education.; Vocational education.; University of Michigan. Occupational Education Program.
- Records
  - History (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1919-1978, 2 volumes; 1 folders (Box 1)
  - Staff Meeting Minutes
    - 1950-1965, 4 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1965-1980, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Reports to the President 1949-1978, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Reports to the Summer Session 1952-1963 (Box 2)
  - Reports to the State Office of Vocational Education (Box 2)
  - Reports to the Extension Service (Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1964-1978, 7 folders (Box 2)
  - Chairman's Correspondence
    - John T. Oldbert
      - General (Box 2)
      - Frederick W. Bertolaet (Box 2)
      - Wilbur J. Cohen (Box 2)
    - Madge Attwood
      - General (Box 2)
      - Frederick W. Bertolaet (Box 2)
      - Wilbur J. Cohen (Box 2)
    - Ella M. Bowen (Box 2)
  - Program Review
    - Final Report and Response 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General 1978-1979, 3 folders (Box 2)
      - With Dean 1978-1981, 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate Program
    - Program Development
      - 1966-1967 (Box 2)
      - 1968-1980, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Artification, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Occupational Teacher Education Program, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Vocational -- Industrial Education
    - General, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Advisory Committee for Cooperative Vocational -- Teacher (Box 3)
  - Vocational-technical teacher education curriculum, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Committees
    - Advisory Committee on Occupational Professional Development (Box 3)
    - Marshall Byrn Memorial Library Committee (Box 3)
    - External-Review Committee (Box 3)
    - Appraisal Committee
      - Memoranda of Understanding, Occupational Education Programs 1977-1982 (Box 3)
      - Memoranda of Understanding, other SOE programs (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Occupational Education Doctoral Students Organization (Box 3)
  - Student Representation (Box 3)
  - Program and budget planning 1969 (Box 3)
  - Analysis of staff workloads (Box 3)
  - Centennial celebration of School of Education 1978 (Box 3)
  - State Ad Hoc Driver Education Policy Study Committee 1963-1964, 1 volumes (Box 3)
  - Clippings, circa 1950-1973 from scrapbook of Prof. Ralph C. Wenrich (Box 3)
  - State Directors of Vocational Education (Box 4)
    - Jack J. Harris (Box 4)
    - William B. Hawley (Box 4)
  - Chief of Trade and Industrial Education
    - Harold J. VanWestrienen (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with the office of the Dean
    - April 1950-May 1952 (Box 4)
    - Dean Olson 1953-1962, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - 1969-1979 (Box 4)
  - Vocational Education Faculty
    - Arnold, Joseph P. (Box 4)
    - Bateson, Willard M. (Box 4)
    - Borosage, Lawrence (Box 4)
    - Brown, Daniel P. (Box 4)
    - Dalton, F. W.
      - Genera (Box 4)
      - Professional background (Box 4)
      - Articles, speeches, etc. (Box 4)
    - Diamond, Thomas, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Harris, Norman C. (Box 4)
    - Hodges, Lewis H. (Box 4)
    - Hutchcroft, C. Robert (Box 4)
    - Lanham, Frank (Box 4)
    - Lockette, Rutherford E. (Box 4)
    - Murtland, Cleo (Box 4)
    - Myers, George E. (Box 4)
    - Odbert, John T. (Box 4)
    - Pierce, Hugh F. (Box 4)
    - Rzonca, Chester S. (Box 4)
    - Sonsnith, Henry A. (Box 4)
    - Trytten, John M. (Box 4)
    - Vezzani, A. A. (Box 5)
      - General (Box 5)
      - Data Training Center Tour (Mexico) (Box 5)
      - Foreign assignment, International Cooperation Administration (Africa) (Box 5)
    - Vogler, Daniel E. (Box 5)
  - Japanese Industrial Skills Study Team January 26, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Peace Corps Proposal, Summer 1963 (Box 5)
  - Thailand Peace Corps Information, 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Staff Status, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Brazilian Seminar, 3 folders (Box 5)